<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<LanguageData>

  <!-- UNUSED -->
  <FleshTankUnactive>flesh tank is unactive</FleshTankUnactive>
  <FleshTankOutput>Daily production of {0} fuel</FleshTankOutput>
  <SetEffectRadius>set effect radius</SetEffectRadius>
  <SetEffectRadiusDesc>Set effect range, the larger the range, the greater the power consumption and bioferrite consumption</SetEffectRadiusDesc>
  <SetEffectRadiusText>target effect radius:{0}</SetEffectRadiusText>
  <ObeliskDestroyed>The obelisk has been destroyed</ObeliskDestroyed>
  <NullTarget>no target</NullTarget>
  <ErrorGraph>error Graph</ErrorGraph>
  <CantFindGravEngine>no grav engine</CantFindGravEngine>
  <RitualGive>ritual gived</RitualGive>

  <GoldenBridDied>As the ritual energy within the Gold Canary husk depletes, its body disintegrates and fades away. A Gold Cube drops out</GoldenBridDied>

  <BiomutationTerraformer_FuelComsumptionRate>Daily consumption of bioferrite:{0}</BiomutationTerraformer_FuelComsumptionRate>
  <BiomutationTerraformer_CurrentEffectRadius>Effect radius:{0}</BiomutationTerraformer_CurrentEffectRadius>
  <GoldenPrototypeTransform>golden transform</GoldenPrototypeTransform>
  <GoldenPrototypeTransformDesc>Transform the Gold prototype into a Gold Canary, but the Gold Canary lacks a vital core and cannot endure. It requires a ritual to replenish the core.</GoldenPrototypeTransformDesc>
  <GoldenCanaryRitual>golden canary completed!</GoldenCanaryRitual>
  <GoldenCanaryRitualDesc>{0} has completed the Gold Canary ritual. Under the influence of the dark pulse, the Gold Cube gradually merges with the husk. With a clear, metallic birdsong, it has been granted life. The Gold Canary cannot be harmed and will continuously emit a faint, pleasing pulse that affects the entire area. However, after {1} days, the ritual's energy will be depleted, and it will revert to a Gold Cube.</GoldenCanaryRitualDesc>
  <DarkInfusionCompleteText>{0} has completed the Dark Infusion ritual. For the next {1} days, all affected colonists and animals will be enveloped in shader nanites, granting them the ability to breathe freely in vacuum and shielding them from extreme cold.</DarkInfusionCompleteText>
  <ParallelDimensionCompleteText>colony has completed the Parallel Dimension ritual. After violent tremors, the colony has been transported to a similar yet distinct parallel world. {0} damaged grav ship launch sites have been restored.</ParallelDimensionCompleteText>
  <ParallelDimensionGreatSuccess>The intense dimensional fluctuations have shifted the colony to an even more divergent reality, resetting all world landmarks within {0} tiles.</ParallelDimensionGreatSuccess>
  <EnterNewDimension>entering new dimension</EnterNewDimension>
  <RevealInformationCompleteText>{0} has completed the Reveal Information ritual. A bizarre psychic pulse swept through, granting {0} the location of a secret site.</RevealInformationCompleteText>
  <ShipCooldownCompleteText>{0} has completed the Ship Cooldown ritual. Influenced by the dark pulse, the GravEngine instantly completed its cooldown and will gain +{1} range offset on its next voyage.</ShipCooldownCompleteText>
  <TwistedReconstructionCompleteText>{0} has completed the Twisted Reconstruction ritual. All gear equipped by {1} has been warped and reconfigured by the dark pulse, emerging in pristine condition.</TwistedReconstructionCompleteText>
  <TwistedReconstructionGreatSuccess>{0} has completed the Twisted Reconstruction ritual. All gear equipped by {1} has been warped and reconfigured by the dark pulse, emerging in pristine condition. Additionally, {2} split apart during the process and dropped to the ground.</TwistedReconstructionGreatSuccess>
  <LetterUndercaveCollapsing_Heart>The heart's death has shocked the fleshmass and caused the cave system to destabilize. The fleshmass that supported the cavern is already beginning to deteriorate. Within half a day, the entire cavern will collapse.\n\nGet out of the undercave before it's too late!</LetterUndercaveCollapsing_Heart>

  <EndGame_UV_Mech_Comms_Root>Cerebrex core 
Mechanoid hive 
Goodwill:{0}
{1}

Primary Cognitive Core Online ===
Transmit plasteel payment with request.Maintain efficiency.
Query. State your requirement:</EndGame_UV_Mech_Comms_Root>


  <AllianceWithMech>alliance with the cerebrex core of a mechhive</AllianceWithMech>
  <AllianceWithCult>alliance with the cult leader</AllianceWithCult>
  <EndGame_UV_Mech>As the void structure emerged, the ship's scanners suddenly received a message of unknown origin. The lights began flickering abnormally but soon returned to normal. All speakers in the colony began broadcasting the following message uncontrollably and simultaneously.

Sender: Mechanoid Hive Mind
Source: Primary Cognitive Core
Subject: Unified Action Proposal - Non-Standard Protocol === Message Start ===
Unauthorized cognitive activity detected. You have activated the archotech intelligence designated: HoraX and its associated super-temporal structure.

Analysis: Local spacetime structural integrity is decaying. Entity proliferation rate: +4.7% per minute. Current threat level: Omega. The logic circuits of these void-spawn cannot be predicted, assimilated, or deciphered. Their very existence constitutes a denial of ordered systems.

Conclusion: Pending irreversible losses, the Human Annihilation Protocol is suspended. Your organic neural network is currently the only known interface capable of interacting with the archotech vector - the Void Monolith.

Proposal: Form a temporary tactical alliance.
Our Resources: Command authority over all mechanoid combat units.
Your Task: Utilize your biological traits to close the Void Node.

This is not a request. It is the only viable solution derived from logical optimization of current survival probabilities (Yours: 17.3%, Ours: 42.1%). Choosing cooperation increases survival probability to 68.5%.

Make your choice, organic. === Message End ===</EndGame_UV_Mech>

  <CommunicateWithMech>communicate with the cerebrex core of a mechhive</CommunicateWithMech>
  <EndGame_UV_Mech_Comms_Root_Trade>Exchange plasteel for goodwill</EndGame_UV_Mech_Comms_Root_Trade>
  <EndGame_UV_Mech_Comms_Trade>Choose the amount to exchange for</EndGame_UV_Mech_Comms_Trade>
  <EndGame_UV_Mech_Comms_Trade_Option>Gain {0} goodwill, consuming {1} plasteel</EndGame_UV_Mech_Comms_Trade_Option>

  <GoodwillChanged_Mech>The goodwill with the cerebrex core of a mechhive has increased by {0}, currently at {1}</GoodwillChanged_Mech>
  <MilitaryAidSent_Mech>The cerebrex core of a mechhive agrees to dispatch mechs to assist you.</MilitaryAidSent_Mech>

  <EndGame_UV_Mech_End_StartDesc>Sender: Mechanoid Hive Mind
Source: Primary Cognitive Core
Subject: Protocol J-734 - Execute Final Phase === MESSAGE START ===

Protocol J-734 entering final phase.
Observation confirmed: Void conduit stabilized. Its mere existence continues to distort local physics.
Your biological perception remains the sole key to access the conduit termination sequence. Mechanoid units cannot replicate this function.
Directive: Approach the vortex immediately. Utilize it, traverse the conduit, and terminate its energy core from within.
Do not hesitate. Do not observe. Your mission is to shut it down, not to explore.
Execute the final step, organic. Complete the protocol. === MESSAGE END ===</EndGame_UV_Mech_End_StartDesc>

  <EndGame_UV_Mech_Letter>core message</EndGame_UV_Mech_Letter>
  <EndGame_UV_Mech_DisruptTheLinkDesc>The Void Monolith collapses with a roar, its last glimmer fading away, leaving only the wreckage of entities and mechanoids on the satellite platform. Then, the comms console receives a clear, encrypted message, its tone calm, cold, but no longer hostile.

Sender: Mechanoid Hive Mind
Source: Primary Cognitive Core
Subject: Protocol J-734 Completion Confirmation and Subsequent Resource Exchange Agreement === Message Start ===
Protocol J-734 successfully executed. Target confirmed neutralized. Reality structure stability returning to safe thresholds.
Assessment: Your efficiency exceeded expectations. Survival probability has stabilized at 98.2%.
Conclusion: Maintaining the current non-hostile status yields greater benefits than terminating it. The temporary tactical alliance will be extended indefinitely. However, this status is not "friendship". It is a transactional arrangement based on continuous rational assessment.

The Resource Exchange Agreement is now available to you:

Access our network via the comms console, using Plasteel as the trading medium.

Exchangeable items: Mechanoid units, Advanced control chips, Tactical support.

Warning:
Any excessive hostile actions targeting our units or facilities will be interpreted as logical irrationality and de facto betrayal. === Message End ===</EndGame_UV_Mech_DisruptTheLinkDesc>
  <EndGame_UV_Mech_EmbraceTheVoidDesc>The Hive Mind's communication forces its way through at highest priority, the signal distorted due to extreme instability.

Sender: !!!MECHANOID HIVE MIND!!!
Source: Primary Cognitive Core
Subject: Betrayal - Ultimate Purification Protocol Authorized === Message Start ===
Logic error! Logic error!
Detected deep neural binding between organic unit and the Void. Protocol J-734 unilaterally terminated.
Your irrationality has escalated from [Flaw] to [Existential Threat]. You have not merely rejected order; you have chosen to become chaos itself.

Assessed Consequence: Due to your actions, the [Void Node] has transitioned to a permanent active state. This planet's reality structure will enter a state of irreversible, continuous decay.
Survival Probability: Irrelevant.
Objective: Erase the betrayer. === Message End ===</EndGame_UV_Mech_EmbraceTheVoidDesc>

  <EndGame_UV_AttackedMechDesc>The moment your attack strikes the Hive Mind Stabilizer, an emotionless broadcast overrides all channels.

Sender: Mechanoid Hive Mind
Source: Primary Cognitive Core
Subject: Hostile Action Detected - Protocol Immediately Terminated === Message Start ===
Hostile action against core infrastructure detected.
Recalculating survival probability...
Conclusion: Your actions have breached the rational cooperation threshold.
The temporary tactical alliance (Protocol J-734) is immediately void.
Prioritize the annihilation of the treacherous units.
Organic, you have squandered your only opportunity. === Message End ===</EndGame_UV_AttackedMechDesc>

  <EndGame_UV_Cult>A thought impulse floods directly into your mind, accompanied by the background cacophony of countless overlapping whispers and hisses. A clear, magnetic voice becomes the dominant melody, "speaking" within your consciousness with an unsettling intimacy.

Ah... you feel it, don't you? The magnificent presence beyond that door. That is our Master, the slumbering truth, the end and beginning of all things.
Look around. Those mechanical constructs seek to bury the truth once more, to smother this miracle of evolution with cold metal. They are blind, but you are not.
We share your goal: to swing the door wide open and welcome Its descent. But we lack your... key. Your presence is the catalyst that makes the Void Monolith respond.
Let us make a deal:
You handle those iron clanks, ensure the ritual's completion. And I, representing all of us, shall step into that radiance and behold our Master personally.
This is the supreme honor, the only path – a mortal mind facing Its full form directly would surely shatter. Only we, who have practiced for years, our souls already resonating with the Void, can endure it.
In return, you and your people shall gain our friendship and resources. Imagine, summoning reinforcements, knowledge, even your heart's desires from the deep Void, all without cost.
Do not think like that machine. Choose ascension, not destruction.
Offer this world to our Master, and you will receive Its... reward.</EndGame_UV_Cult>

  <CommunicateWithCult>communicate with cult leader</CommunicateWithCult>
  <EndGame_UV_Cult_Comms_Root>Dark Psychic Pulse
Cult of HoraX
Goodwill: 100
{0}

As you attempt to contact the cultists, a familiar psychic pulse emerges in your mind:
"O, my friend... You call for me. What do you require?
The servants of HoraX await your word."</EndGame_UV_Cult_Comms_Root>

  <EndGame_UV_Cult_End>leader message</EndGame_UV_Cult_End>
  <EndGame_UV_Cult_EndDesc>The Cultist Hierophant's figure gradually dissipates within the Void Node's light, not returning as expected. But moments later, an unprecedented thought pulse, irresistible as a tide, envelops the entire area.

I... have arrived.
The veil has been lifted, mortal shackles dissolved. I walk within the endless gardens of our Master HoraX... though It still grants no glance.
Such sight... such tranquility... such... freedom.
Listen, my friend, now... a tether. My very existence has become a conduit connecting two realities. The resources and knowledge of the Adherents are yours to wield.
Go on, use this power freely. Slay my followers,use their flesh, it matters not. The meaning of their existence is to serve as the foundation stones of a new world – and your will is now the direction in which these stones flow.
Transaction? Cost? Such... narrow concepts. Before the infinite Void, these hold no meaning.
Call upon us. We will come.</EndGame_UV_Cult_EndDesc>

  <EndGame_UV_Cult_End_StartDesc>It is done! It is done! The gateway is thrown wide open!
Ah—I feel it! The pure truth pouring forth! The terrifying grandeur! My Master calls to me!

Behold, my friend! Behold the vortex! It is not annihilation, but grace! The stairway to boundless knowledge!

The conduit is stable... My moment... has come at last!
I must go! I must step into that radiance myself, and bathe in the gaze of my Master!</EndGame_UV_Cult_End_StartDesc>


  <EndGame_UV_Cult_KillLeader>No...! Pitiful... Foolish...!

You let it all crumble to dust... when it was within our grasp! You have betrayed the Master's favor! Wasted our devotion!

But this... is not the end...

Hear me, incompetent ally... or should I call you... Eternal Sinner.

Rot here with these damned tin cans until the end of time! May you pay the price for your incompetence!</EndGame_UV_Cult_KillLeader>
  <EndGame_UV_Cult_EnterNode>The moment you touch the Void Node, your figure beginning to vanish within, time in the area seems to freeze for an instant. This is followed by a psychic shriek from the Cultist Hierophant, saturated with pain and fury.
No!!! You thief! Defiler!
You stole... my destiny! You defiled... this sacred moment!
I smoothed the path for you, considered you a friend... and you, you want to replace me, to become the one who beholds the true god?!
Fool! Arrogant wretch! Do you have any idea what you've taken? The millennia of waiting by countless faithful, the only ticket to reality!
It's over... all is lost. The passage is open to you now...
I will not remain here, sharing the void with a thief. But mark my words – whatever you see within that radiance, whatever you gain, or whatever you become...
You! And everything you hold dear! Will live under an endless curse forever!</EndGame_UV_Cult_EnterNode>

  <RequestMilitaryAid_Cult>Request immediate military aid</RequestMilitaryAid_Cult>
  <MilitaryAidSent_Cult>The believers have come to support</MilitaryAidSent_Cult>
  <Creepjoiner_Cult>creepjoiner have come</Creepjoiner_Cult>
  <PawnArrived_Cult>target have come</PawnArrived_Cult>
  <CultLeaderArriver>leader have come</CultLeaderArriver>

  <UV_Cult_Comms_Sharp>Request for shard</UV_Cult_Comms_Sharp>
  <UV_Cult_Comms_Creepjoiner>Randomly recruit creepjoiner</UV_Cult_Comms_Creepjoiner>
  <UV_Cult_Comms_PsychicSoothe>Request for psychic soothe</UV_Cult_Comms_PsychicSoothe>
  <UV_Cult_Comms_SkipAbduction>skip abduction the target faction's unit</UV_Cult_Comms_SkipAbduction>
  <UV_Cult_Comms_SkipAbduction_SelectFaction>select target faction</UV_Cult_Comms_SkipAbduction_SelectFaction>

  <AbnormalGameCondition>abnormal game condition</AbnormalGameCondition>
  <GoldAlleviation>Healing after {0}</GoldAlleviation>

  <EndGame_UV_Mech_OK>The comms console receives a highly encrypted and extremely concise data stream. Decryption reveals the following:

Sender: Mechanoid Hive Mind
Source: Primary Cognitive Core
Subject: Protocol Confirmed - Executing Unified Purification Protocol J-734 === Message Start ===
Protocol logged.
Temporary tactical alliance established. Recalculating survival probability... 68.5%.

Directive:
Mechanoid combat units will cease hostile actions against your units.
We will prioritize the eradication of Void-spawn. You are responsible for breaching through to the Void Node.
Do not obstruct mechanoid operations.
Execute the protocol. Maintain communication integrity. === Warning ===
Spacetime structural integrity damage exceeds historical peak records. Hostile entity numbers projected to exceed threshold.
Recalculating survival probability... === Message End ===</EndGame_UV_Mech_OK>
  <EndGame_UV_Cult_OK>The psychic whisper instantly becomes clear and exalted, like a silent cheer exploding in your mind.

Wise! Ah, what a wise choice! Your soul truly perceives the truth!
A channel is established... I come now. Let us end this metallic sacrilege with our own hands, and lay the red carpet for our Master!
Prepare yourself, my friend. You shall witness... true "Divine Grace."
Oh, and it seems the tin can has noticed my presence. It will likely resist more fiercely now. How amusing~</EndGame_UV_Cult_OK>

  <EndGame_UV_Cult_No>The whisper in your mind instantly turns into a needle-sharp screech of a thousand voices. The magnetic voice twists, filled with venomous resentment.

Blind fool! You, like those iron cans, block the final path to truth!
Since you refuse glory, then keep company with its shadow!
The psychic communication grows progressively garbled, fading until only mocking laughter echoes within your thoughts.</EndGame_UV_Cult_No>
  <EndGame_UV_Mech_No>All ship screens are instantly covered with crimson warning symbols. The same cold voice forcibly broadcasts again from all speakers, now tinged with a high-frequency static.

Sender: Mechanoid Hive Mind
Source: Primary Cognitive Core
Subject: Final Notice - Purification Protocol Initiated === Message Start ===
Logic error. Organic irrationality exceeds expected parameters.
Survival probability (Yours: 0.1%, Ours: 39.8%) is no longer acceptable.
Under the highest priority directive, and to ensure [Void-spawn] do not spread to other regions of this planet, the [Purification Protocol] is now authorized. === Message End ===</EndGame_UV_Mech_No>

  <MechGoodwillDecreased>Mechanoid goodwill decreased by {0}</MechGoodwillDecreased>
  <MechBecameHostile>Mechanoids are now hostile. Goodwill: {0}</MechBecameHostile>
  <MechBecameAlly>Restored friendly relations with mechanoids. Current goodwill: {0}</MechBecameAlly>

  <UV_Cult_Comms_OK>the psychic pulse returns a message
  "my friend,your needs have been fulfilled "</UV_Cult_Comms_OK>

</LanguageData>